What would Frank do?
Given that she's carrying his child.
I've always promised
to tell you the truth.
Transparency is the
cornerstone of my presidency.
And in that spirit, I feel compelled
to share the following.
For some weeks now,
the Justice Department has
been investigating allegations
that the former president, my husband,
falsely inflated 2016 election
day dangers in several states
that may have played a
role in tipping the results.
This news, as you can imagine,
has caused a widow's
dark night of the soul.
Madam President!
This used to be my office.
That was my desk.
The couch is different, but I slept here
more nights than I care to remember.
Congressman Underwood's
desk was right through there.
He never slept.
Never button the bottom.
- Madam President!
- Sarah, yes.
Ma'am, to follow up. What
specific action, if any,
are you planning to take,
since your husband is...
Dead.
Well, everything is on the table.
Up to and including a
posthumous indictment.
- Larry.
- But, Madam President,
if you're calling the
election results into question,
what does that mean for your presidency?
This is the highest office in the land.
Public service is a sacred privilege,
and no one is above the law.
Not the father of my child, not me.
Marcus.
Were you given any warning about
this article that just came out?
By Janine Skorsky?
- I don't know what you're referring to.
- It was posted as you were speaking.
The headline reads,
"Former President Underwood
excluded his wife from his will."
Would you care to comment?
Well, I can't comment on what
I haven't seen. Thank you.
The source named in the
piece is Douglas Stamper.
I have known Douglas
since he became my husband's
right hand man over 20 years ago.
And it is no secret
that he's been having
a difficult time lately.
Emotionally, above all else.
And when I pardoned him months
ago, it was based on compassion.
I feel for the man, I do.
But Doug Stamper will never be
the one to lead us to the truth.
"The former president apparently
handwrote an 11th hour will,
technically known as a holographic will,
with instructions that his estate
be left to his former Chief
of Staff Douglas Stamper."
Does it say anything about what's in it?
"The specifics of the
will are not yet public,
but in an exclusive
interview with Mr. Stamper,
he promised to reveal
the contents 'soon.'"
That'll be all for now.
Get White House counsel.
No, no, actually get my
personal lawyer on the phone now.
Yes, ma'am. And Assistant
Director Green is here,
but he insisted that his...
Madam President.
Let me introduce you to my wife
Abby and this is our son Jackson.
Hello.
Abby's such a fan, we were
hoping to take a picture.
Of course.
I wanted my family here
with me when I let you know,
I'm leaving the Bureau.
I already submitted my
letter of resignation.
Nathan, we can't possibly accept that.
Please, President Hale. I'm begging you.
Lynn, can you come in here, please?
Nathan, I insist we speak
about this one-on-one.
Can you give us a moment?
I'm sorry I failed you
as far as the desert,
but I can't do this anymore.
- Nathan...
- I've made up my mind.
It's better for both
of us if I go quietly.
I'm sure you're looking forward
to walking Jackson to
his first day of school.
I am, ma'am.
Well, my feelings haven't changed.
I want Doug to finally,
finally get the help
he so desperately needs.
You're right to be concerned.
There are some crazy people out there.
In my last conversation with Doug,
he told me entities had approached him,
hoping to recruit him. Abby.
You should cancel your
upcoming public appearances.
- Here to see an old friend.
- The president said, "Doug Stamper
will never be the one to lead us
to the truth." You care to comment?
It must serve the president to
paint me as some sort of crazy man.
Bu I'm sorry to disappoint her, I
am of right mind, and she knows it.
In terms of a revised will,
who knows about its contents?
- Why don't you ask her that question?
- Sir, how did you become aware of it?
I was with him the night he died.
He asked me to his
suite at the Hay-Adams.
He told me he no longer had faith
in his wife's ability
to serve as president.
And President Underwood,
the real President Underwood,
kept an audio diary.
Pieces of which I've heard.
Then let's find a court
that will rule in our favor.
... Stamper, former Chief of Staff
to President Francis Underwood,
recorded earlier today.
Let's turn to our panel for their
take on the claim that the leak...
... remember, this is a troubled man.
We can't take everything he
says at face value, right?
The question is, what is
Stamper's endgame here?
- Why the whole attack on President Hale...
- What?
- He was supposed to provoke her.
- He walked away from murder charges.
- Don't forget that...
- Mark...
- I don't have time to read your mind.
- I tried to warn you.
I've worked with this
guy. We could be exposed.
- Do you trust me, my instincts...
- Yes, of course I do.
That has nothing to do with
evaluating the risk he is becoming.
He's unhinged, Annette.
Unhinged is what's called for.
Contain him. That's your job.
Hey.
Annette!
What's going on?
If my son were anyone else in
this country, he'd be out by now.
No, what's going on here?
Between us?
We're having sex again.
Until it seems like a bad idea, again.
- Hey, listen to me...
- That bitch
is tipping the scales
when it comes to Duncan.
And there's no way he
can get a fair hearing,
until she's gone.
Okay, hold on. Just, um...
Can you back up a few words?
How far back?
Uh, "Moments like this require... "
What is it?
"Someone who will act. Who
will do the unpleasant thing."
You know what? Can you
just let me hear it?
No.
Why not?
I can't. It's...
What are you doing?
Nothing, I... Nothing.
Look, we don't have to
go ahead with this. Okay?
And whatever you need to
figure out, you should.
Like, can't you just leave him alone?
- What do you think I am?
- Look, I know exactly what you are.
She's gonna come after you.
"Requires someone who will act.
Who will do the unpleasant
thing, the necessary thing.
Don't be fooled by her beautiful face.
My wife is ruthless."
"The most ruthless woman I've
ever met. If people only knew."
We've filed an injunction.
But Skorsky's saying her source
believes the material belongs to him.
- This is insane.
- Unless someone produces evidence of a will,
- there's no...
- Why are we even taking this seriously?
I am confident I can
silence her with a gag order.
But once a thing is in print,
- any other news outlet has the right to...
- Print? This isn't print, Geraldine.
- Can't we just shut down the site?
- No, ma'am. I don't think we can.
My advice, let's depose.
Get Mr. Stamper under oath.
- If he perjures himself...
- No. That's exactly what he wants.
He wants a public forum.
And he's been through enough already.
Madam President, I have to ask.
And I will ask you this
in front of your attorney.
Is it your position
that you were entirely
unaware of your husband's...
- You don't have to answer that.
- No, no, I want to.
I don't know if he did
it for his sake or mine,
but he never told me a thing.
Ma'am, in United States v. Nixon...
I swear on his unborn child.
Well, there's no doubt that
there's areas of the company
she's not quite as well versed in.
Partly my fault, our...
Our father didn't believe in succession.
Are you saying you don't
think your sister deserves...
No. That's not what I'm saying.
If anything, when I
talk about succession,
I'm talking about this presidency.
Let's face it, our Commander In Chief,
who basically inherited
the job from her husband,
is acting like a goddamn monarch.
When...
When a tyrant pretends
to be transparent,
nation beware.
And these...
These comments,
these public comments from Doug
Stamper make nothing but sense.
I mean, follow the complicity.
So, do you have any
advice for President Hale?
Yes. Abdicate.
- Oh. Come on now, Bill.
- No, no. Listen
it wouldn't be the worst
thing for this country
if she didn't finish out her term.
Wow.
If that's what was fated for her.
- Mr. Shepard...
- Listen,
I was flipping around
the channels last night,
and I came across The Alamo.
I know it's not a great movie,
but when John Wayne chokes
up saying "Republic...
Bill Shepherd, shut the fuck up.
Reach out to the others.
Remind them of the perils of loose lips.
Nathan Green was in a meeting
hosted by Annette Shepherd.
I don't get rattled easily,
but the secrecy around this
one, who was there and why,
is more than I have ever come across.
I suspect there were some very
powerful people in that room.
Douglas Stamper?
I don't know yet.
Anything else?
Walter, you have worked
with us from the beginning.
Yes. I liked Frank.
So, I'm curious.
How did you pull it off?
Oh, Claire,
my calling is a practical one.
I don't judge. I don't question. I
simply work for the highest bidder.
I'm agnostic, but this
virtual landscape is new to me.
And someone out there
is working very hard to
make Frank look very bad.
Listen, it's just a lot
of noise at the moment.
It's not only about him.
How will you manage to separate
yourself from all this shit?
All that's left is Doug to connect me.
Be careful, Claire.
Oh, you guys.
I really didn't wanna have
to have to do this, but...
An extreme faction of
the ICO terrorist group
made an attempt to purchase
a nuclear device in Pakistan.
That's a fact.
- Madam President, all due respect...
- Maria, I know you're new to this,
but please don't ever use
that expression with me.
"All due respect" means
precisely the opposite.
Ma'am, it's just that this threat
remains squarely in the
category of a potential...
The intent is there.
Until we have confirmation
that the deal has...
Our intelligence has told us that
they will regroup and try again.
This goes back to the warning
from Rafiq Nasser two months ago.
Now acting Secretary Gallagher and I
have been keeping a close watch
on this threat ever
since Nancy took over
for Nora at Homeland.
And in the spirit of
the full transparency
this administration is embracing,
we're going to take it public.
Ma'am. Frankly, I'm concerned.
From a strategic perspective,
if ICO doesn't act, we
appear to be crying wolf.
But on the other hand, are we
putting ourselves in a position
where we're daring them to act?
We don't want to appear reckless.
I couldn't sleep last night.
For obvious national
security reasons, of course,
but...
also because the baby kept me awake.
And for some reason...
the word "misogynist"
popped into my mind.
And I was trying to think
of the word for the opposite.
You know, the word for
when a person hates men.
Does anyone around this
table know that word is?
The word for when a person hates men?
Anybody?
I had to go and look it up.
"Misandrist."
And no one really knows that word
because it's not used in our culture.
So what I'm getting at, is maybe
we all, regardless of our gender,
would do well to examine the
pre-conceived notions that we have
about who can and cannot
act as Commander In Chief.
There you go.
They're from a place
called the Federalist Pig.
I don't know it.
Well, I've been told it is the
next best thing to Freddy's.
I'm good. You want some?
No, they're for you.
Doyle has been asking around about you.
Now we can shut him down.
But...
Yeah, come on, give me one. I mean...
What kind of man says no to ribs, right?
The articles and the press conferences.
A little goes a long way, Doug.
A lot of people,
in a way, the whole country,
we're relying on you.
Seth,
I can take care of myself.
Can you pass that sauce?
You must be so alone.
Do you even have anyone around
anymore that you can trust?
What are you playing at?
"Surely, she saw it all. The killing.
The lying," says Frank at minute six.
Doug, you and me have
to have a come to Jesus.
Agreed. Stop publicly accusing
him or it's all gonna come down.
All I'm trying to do is
seek the truth these days.
Minute 76... "Before I
ever made any big moves,
I always ran them by my wife."
I like the sound of your
voice, Doug. It's so soothing.
I never really thought about it before,
but in just this way,
you remind me of Francis.
The one thing I really
miss is his voice.
It was always my
favorite thing about him.
No matter what he would say,
the sound of his voice made me feel like
everything was going to be all right.
It's not.
Besides Annette, who else was there?
I'm the only one who can save you, Doug.
"And then he asked if
I had no faith in God.
I said, 'You have it wrong.
It's God who has no faith in us.'"
Minute 14. Would you like
me to play it for you?
Drop the investigation and apologize
for what you're doing to him
or more of this is gonna come out.
I'm gonna press play.
I want you to hear it.
My security team just informed me
that Russian soldiers are firing
- at American Special Forces, Viktor.
- They invaded the coast,
which violates
agreements you and I made.
- Preventing a nuclear device from...
- Did you orchestrate this, Claire?
For what? To distract
from your husband's diary?
And don't act like that
would be beneath you.
I don't believe motherhood
automatically makes a woman a saint.
- Rafiq Nasser...
- Is dead.
We hit him with a drone
strike an hour ago.
He was providing us with
necessary intelligence.
That you provided him with first.
The threat is real.
I'll have my people, the
GRU, take it from here.
No, you won't.
Look, Claire, just...
worry about having your baby now.
I've always been entertained
by your arrogance.
It's like watching some
movie, just out of date.
If a rogue element gets their
hands on a nuclear device, Viktor,
I will strike first.
What time is it there now?
Must be close to sunrise, huh?
Just about.
If you drop an atom bomb,
our world, your daughter's world...
That sun will never look
the same again, Claire.
What time is it there?
Uh...
I'm about to have lunch.
And what are you having?
Oh, a salad.
Cucumbers and tomatoes, a bit of feta.
Some Spanish olive oil
and herbs from Tangiers.
I don't eat bread anymore, you know.
We never had a proper meal, you and I.
- Not really.
- I'll have to oppose you now, openly at the UN.
And at every turn.
Privately, I...
I will miss you.
As I made clear to President Petrov,
I will not have terrorists
waltzing out of the desert
with an atomic bomb.
It's time for me to treat you
all like the adults you are.
The truth is...
I'm not the only one who's in danger.
No one's safe. Not really.
Not ever.
Does that mean a nuclear strike?
The first one since Nagasaki?
If need be, yes.
Terry.
You've become a vocal
critic of the president.
Even before your arrest.
Actually, the first time you went
public was to support legislation
limiting her powers.
Which is now more urgent than ever.
And recently, as you await trial,
you got into some more hot
water with your comments.
Yes, I misspoke.
But let's face it.
This president is fatal.
I mean, she's out there
evoking end of days.
And with her in office, that is
exactly where this country is headed.
And what am I?
Some antiquated soul because
I still believe in family?
Listen, if you want to do something
in this country about poverty,
family.
Crime, family.
Education, family. It's family.
My parents had dinner at six
o'clock. Every single night.
They didn't care where you were,
what the hell you were doing.
Dinner was at six, goddamnit.
And when's the last time you
and your sister had dinner?
That is a fair question.
And it has been some time
since we sat across from each other.
How you doing, Bill?
Depends on the day.
And the dose.
I brought you some pastries,
from Poupon, Georgetown.
I know you have a soft spot for those.
Well, I don't do sugar anymore.
It's... fuel for the tumor.
You can have one, if you want.
No, I'm good.
Twenty years ago,
I probably would have sat down...
and written out my memoirs,
instead of...
trying to just get it
out there any way I can.
I thought she would have come out.
I'm sorry. She sent me.
Does she want me to stop?
The opposite.
She wants you to keep
hitting the president hard...
so that she can come out against you.
Is this gonna be a mess?
Could be.
When did it happen?
That we were the ones catching up.
Were we not paying attention?
Not enough.
Francis was a son of a bitch.
But he was a talented son of a bitch.
He saw her coming.
He just couldn't stop himself.
Or her.
Where do you think we're
gonna be in ten years, Mark?
Huh? Come on. I'm asking everybody.
- For obvious reasons.
- You think about it more than I do.
Fat, wasted and distracted.
Might be a good night out,
but it's no way to live a life.
Come on, ten years?
I don't know.
Things don't really change, Bill.
They just...
They just fade away, man.
God, I'm angry.
I heard your husband's voice.
Douglas Stamper came to us.
Offered up Francis' diaries,
snippets of which Doug played for me.
And to tell you the truth, I
considered using it against you.
But I don't think it should ever
find its way into the public sphere.
- Forgive my surprise.
- I'm not my brother.
Bill's become bad for democracy.
Like Francis was.
The world loves a cat fight,
but I say let's deny
them the satisfaction.
It's not too late for us.
You know, you're right. Let's
not give them what they want.
Fuck them all.
Oh. Sorry, Angel.
They hear things, you know.
There have been studies.
Is it amazing?
It is.
She's an active little thing.
May I?
Sure.
Oh, she's kicking.
We'll take care of Doug.
I don't believe your support.
You're a bad liar, Annie.
And you tried to kill her.
You have my son.
How are you gonna do it?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Tell me who the others are
and I will let Duncan go.
- He's innocent, as am I.
- God, please.
This so-called nuclear crisis.
You're worse than Frank.
Oh. She's kicking again.
It's like she senses
we're nearing the end.
The only question, Doug,
is if you're their plan
A, what's their plan B?
If Francis were here, we'd know.
Yes. Well, if he was going to kill me,
- how would he do it?
- He'd find an opportunity you provided.
He was always three
steps ahead, wasn't he?
Francis Underwood...
Maybe he still is.
Have I been keeping him alive?
Just how far am I willing to go?
I'm having second thoughts.
Am I sure this is a good idea?
Yes.
What if I'm carrying a
demon seed or something?
The odds are 50-50.
So tired of talking about Francis.
I miss my boyfriend Reed.
- I do too, sometimes, but...
- Reed wanted too much.
Francis gave me permission to hunger.
Because he felt it himself.
All the time. Insatiable.
Everyone thinks I should feel sated.
Then he said, "No, Claire,
be as hungry as me."
And so I ate him?
He ate himself.
Doug Stamper?
Am I going to eat him?
- Herr God.
- Herr Lucifer.
Beware.
You know, I always thought...
- maybe one day, you know, but...
- Put it back.
- What?
- The picture. It belongs on the fridge.
Okay, sorry.
You know, if there is
anything that I can do.
- I mean, in case it doesn't go as planned.
- Can you please stop moving?
I'm a little worked up, all right?
Claire Hale Underwood
lived and then she died.
- She's no different from anyone else.
- Yeah.
Well, I'm not sure the world's
gonna see it the way you do.
If this breaks right, you can be a hero.
Don't spin me, Seth.
How do they plan to do me in?
Seth?
Look.
I'm gonna say this to you.
Not because we're friends.
But because of everything that
we've been through together.
You're an asshole.
You don't have to be a part
of this, if you don't want to.
You saying that for me or for you?
Maybe both.
I don't know who it is...
but they have someone
inside the White House.
Military always hated her.
Hmm? That's one thing.
Fuck 'em all.
What about the two of us? We just leave.
Where do you wanna go?
Hello.
How does he look?
He's fine. He's sure
that she'll invite him in.
Put him on.
Doug.
- Yeah.
- What extraordinary times these are.
I wish I could be there
to shake your hand.
Annette, I want to make
something very clear.
I'm not doing this for you.
We'll be sure to move him
from Gaffney to Arlington.
And help fund the Library.
And, Doug, given your recent struggles,
nine or ten years from
now, you could be out.
And I want to thank you.
Seth.
Yes.
Everything is set from our side.
The quarterback is standing by.
And Duncan?
Is going to have to wait.
What else did she say?
Nothing.
Just...
everything's in place.
Later.
Seth.
It's not going to go like you think.
No.
I never liked talking to
you in the first place.
From what I hear, you were right
to cancel your public appearances.
- You think so?
- I do, ma'am.
I think the White House is the
safest place for you to be right now.
Nathan, you're a liar.
Do me a favor. Kiss your
sweet baby's forehead for me.
Our intelligence confirms the hand
off is on the verge of taking place.
And our intelligence says that's not so.
We're talking about a
20-mile radius of sand.
Unreachable by conventional means.
I'll have my forces
coordinate with yours, okay?
I'm not asking for
your permission, Viktor.
Look, Claire. I can see how
eager you are to show your enemies
just how powerful you are.
But, please,
please don't do this.
I know you,
the things you've done.
Think how the world will judge you.
As if you have any credibility
with the world stage.
Prepare a statement.
Ma'am, I need to object.
Pardon me?
The public is aware
we're prepared to strike.
We don't need to alarm them further.
I will not be a part of
this... this fabrication.
Alert the military aide.
I want him ready and
waiting with the briefcase.
A targeted strike will
destabilize the region
for decades to come...
and it will create a distrust
that will ripple through
Europe and much of Asia.
Markets will be rocked. Yes,
the consequences will be grave.
But it has come to my attention...
that there is a plot against me.
Someone in my White House
is planning to betray me.
And until I find out who that is,
I will not reconsider my position here.
Ma'am? Something arrived
for you from Doug Stamper.
It was passed through security.
Thank you.
- Yes.
- The men in uniform don't support you.
I want the White House emptied out.
Other than yourselves, minimal
and essential staff only.
- All visitors need to be cleared by me.
- Yes, ma'am.
Are you fucking kidding
me? Are you standing me up?
God bless you, man.
But this is not what you promised me.
And you can tell the president
that she can send an
army of lawyers at me,
but I won't be buried.
I am not going to stop.
And I don't know when it will be or how.
But I am going to finish
this godforsaken story, okay?
See, the Harry Brooker painting,
that's my very favorite.
And then there's the Hogarth.
That's 1700's, English.
And from France, the
Chardin, same period.
Maison des Cartes.
There's...
one from the 1800s from Germany
that's very interesting in here.
There, see?
They all have one thing in common.
Children watching,
waiting for the cards to fall.
Seth Grayson.
Annette.
I won't be here for this.
Where would you rather be?
I don't know.
1999.
Tenants Advocacy Group,
south side of Chicago.
But I can't be there, so I don't know.
If you're leaving, leave.
Ma'am.
Thank you, Colonel Flora.
What did they promise you?
- Ma'am, I didn't...
- Quiet.
What took you so long?
May we have the room, please?
- Are you sure, ma'am?
- Yes. It's all right. Thank you.
Doug.
Do we need a drink?
You can't.
Well, desperate times, right?
Here's who wants you dead.
Annette Shepherd had me waiting.
I know who was there.
Thank you.
Whatever happens here...
It's between us.
Doug, I know you. You've
never really had anyone else.
Rachel Posner, but...
How long do you think you're
going to get away with that?
I don't.
What are you going to call her?
I haven't decided yet.
- What do you think?
- Frances Underwood.
Frances with an "e."
That belongs to her.
She ever gonna get to
hear his voice? His words?
No.
And neither is anyone else.
- Her father was a great man, Claire.
- Doug.
How many times did he
even mention your name
in those recordings?
- He was protecting me.
- No.
I'm so sorry you need to believe that.
Do you want it?
I'm the only one left
who knows you, Claire.
You're using that child out there,
acting like the mother of this nation.
I know the truth.
Doug, I'm happy.
Believe me. I'm good.
I want you to know that I forgive you.
It was you, right?
He was coming here to kill you.
And then he was going to go to you next.
I couldn't let you destroy him.
Did you want him to die in
my bed? Was that your plan?
I didn't have a plan.
I didn't know.
I didn't... I didn't know.
I used his meds.
I didn't know how long
it would take, but I...
I knew.
I couldn't let him destroy
everything we built.
I had to protect the
legacy from the man.
He got weak, Doug.
That wasn't your fault.
He made you!
Say it. Say it.
Say it.
I'm not going to give you what you want.
Damn it, Claire. Just say it. Please.
You're happy he's dead, too.
Then say it! Say it!
Say it!
Say it right now.
Let him go, Doug.
I can't!
I'm sorry.
I'm sor...
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
I'm sorry.
It's all right, Doug.
Everything is gonna be all right.
It's all gonna be all right.
There.
No more pain.
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
www.tvsubtitles.net